{"id":"2017_8","name":"Romans2017_8","memoryVerse":"“Yet he did not waver through unbelief regarding the promise of God, but was strengthened in his faith and gave glory to God, being fully persuaded that God had power to do what he had promised.” – Romans 4:20-21 ","dayQuestions":{"one":{"title":"FIRST DAY: Read the notes and the references.","questions":[{"id":"2017_8_1","questionText":"1. What was meaningful to you in the lecture?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_8_2","questionText":"2. What help did you receive from the notes?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"two":{"title":"SECOND DAY: Read Romans 5:1-2.","readVerse":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"5:1-2"}],"questions":[{"id":"2017_8_3","questionText":"3. What does it mean to have peace with God, and how is it accomplished? How is this different from and superior to peaceful circumstances or feelings? ","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_8_4","questionText":"4. What access do believers have through Jesus Christ, and how should this privilege impact your daily life? (See also John 14:6; Ephesians 2:18; 3:12; Hebrews 4:14-16.) ","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"John","verse":"14:6"},{"book":"Ephesians","verse":"2:18"},{"book":"Ephesians","verse":"3:12"},{"book":"Hebrews","verse":"4:14-16"}]},{"id":"2017_8_5","questionText":"5. Christians will see God’s glory in heaven. How might focusing on your “hope of the glory of God” strengthen you, comfort you or give you joy today? (See also Psalm 17:15; Matthew 5:8; 1 John 3:2; Revelation 22:3-4.)","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Psalm","verse":"17:15"},{"book":"Matthew","verse":"5:8"},{"book":"1 John","verse":"3:2"},{"book":"Revelation","verse":"22:3-4"}]}]},"three":{"title":"THIRD DAY: Read Romans 5:3-5.","readVerse":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"5:3-5"}],"questions":[{"id":"2017_8_6a","questionText":"6. a. Why and how can believers glory (rejoice or boast) in suffering?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_8_6b","questionText":"6. b.  How has God used your suffering to produce perseverance, character, hope and a deeper knowledge of His love in you and in those around you?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_8_7","questionText":"7. Why does hope not disappoint us or “put us to shame,” and what role does the Holy Spirit play in this process? ","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"four":{"title":"FOURTH DAY: Read Romans 5:6-8.","readVerse":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"5:6-8"}],"questions":[{"id":"2017_8_8a","questionText":"8. a. Give three words from these verses that describe the condition of those for whom Christ died. Why is this good news?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_8_8b","questionText":"8. b. How do these three words make clear that people cannot save themselves, and what is your personal experience of this? (See also Ephesians 2:1-9.)","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Ephesians","verse":"2:1-9"}]},{"id":"2017_8_9","questionText":"9. How might these verses help you explain why Christianity is unique as compared with other religions and  philosophies?  ","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"five":{"title":"FIFTH DAY: Read Romans 5:9-11.","readVerse":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"5:9-11"}],"questions":[{"id":"2017_8_10","questionText":"10. List various aspects of salvation from these verses.","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_8_11a","questionText":"11. a.  Define “reconciliation.” (If needed, use a dictionary.)","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_8_11b","questionText":"11. b.  Is God reconciled to us or are we reconciled to God, and what does it reveal about God?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_8_12","questionText":"12. How are we saved through Christ’s life, and what words or actions will you use to boast (rejoice) in Him?  (See also Romans 4:25; 6:8-10; 8:34; or other Bible passages you may know.)","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"4:25"},{"book":"Romans","verse":"6:8-10"},{"book":"Romans","verse":"8:34"}]}]},"six":{"title":"SIXTH DAY: Review Romans 5:1-11.","readVerse":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"5:1-11"}],"questions":[{"id":"2017_8_13","questionText":"13. What have you learned about God in this week’s study? How may your group pray for you as you make this truth a part of your life?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_8_14","questionText":"14. Homiletics for group and administrative leaders: Romans 5:1-11","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"5:1-11"}]}]}}}